BENJAMIN HAOS

Milwaukee, WI • 414-202-5364 • benjaminhaos@gmail.com

PROFILE

Well-trained software engineer and developer with Computer Science degree and real-world work experience. Offer keen understanding of real-world business goals and how they apply to developing, rolling out, and supporting applications. Perform at equally high levels on individual projects or within large team environments with collaboration and shared responsibilities. Demonstrated experience with architecture, coding, database programming, and quality assurance efforts.

KEY SKILLS & ABILITIES

Software Engineering	Object Oriented Programming Web Services	
Web Development	Unified Modeling Language (UML)	Quality Assurance
Embedded Software Development	Database Design & Programming	Systems Analysis/Needs Analysis
Software Testing	Database Performance Tuning	Requirements Gathering
Model View Controller (MVC)	Data Modeling	Agile & Waterfall Methodologies

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Java	Fortran & Pascal	XML
C & C++	SQL	JavaScript
Python	HTML5 & CSS3	jQuery & AJAX

PLATFORM EXPERTISE

Cloud Platforms	Amazon Web Services,	Google Cloud,	Google Apr	o Engine, Heroku	, Vagrant, Cloud9

Virtualization VirtualBox, Hyper-V

Databases MongoDB, Microsoft Access

OS Linux (Ubuntu, Debian, Arch), Windows, MacOS X

Development Tools EclipseIDE, Visual Studio, Astah Pro, Visio, Android Studio, App Inventor, Code Bender, Git

Other Docker, Maven, Packer, Chef, Apache, node JS, Spring Framework, Java Spark

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science - Carroll University

3.687 GPA. Cum Laude. Dean's List. Research projects included:

- Led team for simulated insurance software development project using Spring, Java Spark, MongoDB, and Maven Tools
- Programmed functionality for IR remote that bridged control from Amazon Echo to A/V system
- Prototyped and wrote embedded code for touch-activated, dual NFC tag sensing A/C switched power supply
- Developed and administered Java-based CRUD data entry systems utilizing Java Spark and Maven Build Tools

Electrical Engineering Coursework - Ewha Womans University

2015-2016

2017

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ewha University Embedded Systems Lab - Korea	Study-Abroad Intern	2015-2016
Umansky Motor Cars - Milwaukee, WI	Auto Technician & IT Specialist	2009-2013

Portfolio and project examples at www.haos.info